(《浪漫医生》第三季)
(DR. ROMANTIC SEASON 3)
本剧中的人物、地点、组织和事件均为虚构的作品
THE CHARACTERS, PLACES, ORGANIZATIONS, AND
EVENTS IN THIS DRAMA ARE WORKS OF FICTION
一般来说，重要的是要把它做得很好。
Generally speaking,
it's important to make it down well.
但这个该死的东西叫作自豪感
But this darn thing called pride
使得一个人表现得很小气。
makes a man act petty.
看得远一点，明白吗？
Look far ahead, got it?
- 还有......--如果你反正要下去、
- Also…
- If you're going down anyway,
你可能会觉得这样做很酷。...放轻松一点
you might as well look cool doing it.
…loosen up a little!
戴上你的护目镜!
Put your goggles on!
但贪婪和傲慢使你如此努力。
But greed and arrogance
make you try so hard.
- 只有在你变成残骸之后......--明白吗？
- Only after you become a wreck…
- Got it?
......你是否最终能够放下它。
…will you finally be able
to let it go.
这个风...
This wind…
不要跳。不要！不要！
Don't jump. No! Don't!
不要跳，我告诉你
Don't jump, I tell you!
难道一个人就没有办法
Is there no way for a man
看起来很优雅
to look graceful
坠落时？
while falling?
你这话是什么意思？
What do you mean by that?
我加入你们只有一个条件。
There is only one condition
for me to join you.
你将把卜永菊从道达姆医院创伤中心带走。
You will remove Bu Yongju
from Doldam Hospital Trauma Center.
我们不能就你的工资或任何其他条件达成协议吗？
Can't we reach an agreement
with your salary or any other condition?
我不是在要求做交易，朴局长。
I'm not asking to make a deal,
Director Park.
教授，没有金师傅，我们的创伤中心就无法运作。
Professor, we can't run the Trauma Center
without Master Kim.
这是不可想象的。
It's unimaginable.
那么就让我们忘记我们曾经讨论过这个问题。
Then let's forget we ever discussed this.
查晋文教授
PROFESSOR CHA JINMAN
是我。
It's me.
你想什么时候开始？
When do you want to start?
你希望我什么时候开始？
When would you like me to start?
一个星期内怎么样？
How about in one week?
到时候我再跟金师傅说。
I'll talk to Master Kim by then.
当然，你将不得不应对来自其他医生的阻力。
Of course, you will have to deal with
resistance from the other doctors.
我已经准备好应对这么多。
I'm prepared to deal with that much.
并在开始工作前让我了解其他细节。
And let me know about other details
before you start work.
好的。
Okay.
是的，到时候见。
Yes. I'll see you then.
他说他会这样做。
He says he'll do it.
干得好，朴局长。
Good work, Director Park.
- 金师傅。- 什么事？
- Master Kim.
- Yes?
我可以问你为什么吗？
May I ask you why?
你为什么做出这样的决定？
Why did you make such a decision?
你决定我们需要他
You determined that we need him
并想把他带到这里。
and wanted to bring him here.
不过，我还是不希望创伤中心没有你在。
Still, I didn't want the Trauma Center
without you there.
创伤中心...
The Trauma Center…
这是你长期以来的一个梦想。
had been a longtime dream of yours.
剥夺这一点将是一种欺骗。
Taking that away would be cheating.
朴主任。
Director Park.
你知道如何将大象放入冰箱吗？
Do you know how to put
an elephant into a fridge?
答案很简单。
The answer is simple.
打开门。
Open the door.
把大象放进去。然后，关闭门。
Put the elephant inside.
Then, close the door.
金师傅。
Master Kim.
但是，仅仅因为某些东西是简单的
But just because something is simple
并不意味着任何人都能做到这一点。
doesn't mean anyone can do it.
一个简单的解决方案并不容易。
A simple solution doesn't make it easy.
你和我才刚刚抓住了门把手。
You and I
have only just grabbed the doorknob.
查晋文教授!给我儿子的死亡一个答案!
PROFESSOR CHA JINMAN!
GIVE ME AN ANSWER FOR MY SON'S DEATH!
查晋文教授!给我儿子的死亡一个答案!
PROFESSOR CHA JINMAN!
GIVE ME AN ANSWER FOR MY SON'S DEATH!
(第三卷）把大象放在冰箱里，第二部分
(VOLUME 3)
PUTTING AN ELEPHANT IN A FRIDGE, PART 2
这里是道达姆医院的急诊室。
This is the Doldam Hospital ER.
是的，知道了。
Yes, got it.
张医生，三分钟后将有一位急诊病人到达。
Dr. Jang, an emergency patient
is arriving in three minutes.
哦，好的。你能帮他包扎一下吗？
Oh, okay. Can you bandage him up, please?
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
哦，你需要看看八号床的裂缝伤口。
Oh, and you need to look at
the laceration wound in bed eight.
撕裂的伤口？好的。
Laceration wound? Okay.
张医生，二号床的病人的X光片已经出来了。
Dr. Jang, the X-ray is out
for the patient in bed two.
好的。
Okay.
哦，我们应该如何处理这个胃痛的病人？
Oh, what should we do
about the patient with the stomachache?
我会做的。
I'll do it.
张医生！八号床的裂缝伤口。
Dr. Jang!
The laceration wound in bed eight.
- 他们已经等了好一会儿了。- 好的。
- They've been waiting for a while.
- Okay.
医生，有这么多血。
Doctor, there's so much blood.
医生，请看一下这里。
Doctor, please take a look here.
- 医生。- 我们先来的。
- Doctor.
- We were here first.
- 但是这很紧急。- 医生。
- But this is urgent.
- Doctor.
- 请稍等。- 请帮助我们。
- Just a moment.
- Please help us.
- 医生。- 我们先来的。
- Doctor.
- We were here first.
- 医生？- 医生！
- Doctor?
- Doctor!
- 请原谅我。- 医生。
- Excuse me.
- Doctor.
郑仁秀博士和尹爱莲还没有来吗？
Are Dr. Jung Insu
and Yoon Areum not here yet?
荣格博士去参加了一个与主任的会议。
Dr. Jung went to a meeting
with the director.
而尹医生还没有来上班。
And Dr. Yoon hasn't come to work yet.
认真地说...
Seriously…
我们有一个病人!
We have a patient!
发生了一场车祸。
There was a car crash.
腹部有穿透性伤口。血压为80/40。心率120。
A penetrating wound in the abdomen.
BP is 80/40. Heart rate 120.
他的血压太低了。张医生，我们应该怎么做？
His BP is too low.
What should we do, Dr. Jang?
张医生!胃痛的病人怎么办？
Dr. Jang!
What about the stomachache patient?
张医生！八号床的撕裂伤！
Dr. Jang!
The laceration wound in bed eight!
- 张博士！张博士！张博士- 张博士！
- Dr. Jang!
张医生！八号床！
Dr. Jang! Bed eight!
等一下......等一下。
Wait… just a minute.
- 八号床！- 你在做什么？
- Bed eight!
- What are you doing?
- 请快点来!- 这很紧急！
- Please come quickly!
- It's urgent!
- 张博士！张博士！张博士- 张博士！
- Dr. Jang!
在这里！
Over here!
你现在在做什么？
What are you doing right now?
抓紧时间，朋克！
Get a grip, punk!
我们祝你健康
WE WISH YOU GOOD HEALTH
他只是站着睡着了，对吗？
He just fell asleep standing up, right?
我想他甚至做了一个梦。
I think he even had a dream.
你一定很累了，张医生。
You must be very tired, Dr. Jang.
是的...
Yes…
我很好。
I'm okay.
这是一个急诊病人!
It's an emergency patient!
这是一个26岁的男性。他是国家跳台滑雪队的成员。
It's a 26-year-old male.
He's on the national ski jump team.
他在训练中的一次着陆中受伤。
He was injured
while making a landing during training.
他的生命体征是126/82和68。
His vitals are 126/82 and 68.
他似乎没有任何外部伤害、
He doesn't seem to have
any external injuries,
但他正遭受着极度的痛苦。
but he's suffering from extreme pain.
- 让我们把他送进混合手术室。- 好的。
- Let's get him in the hybrid OR.
- Okay.
请在此等候。
Please wait here.
你不去吗？
Aren't you coming?
郑仁秀博士和尹阿伦博士的情况如何？
What about
Dr. Jung Insu and Dr. Yoon Areum?
荣格博士正在与主任开会。
Dr. Jung is in a meeting
with the director.
而尹医生还没有来上班。
And Dr. Yoon hasn't come to work yet.
张博士。
Dr. Jang.
张博士，快点。
Dr. Jang, hurry.
- 哦，你来了。- 是的，你好。
- Oh, you're here.
- Yes, hello.
把那个放在里面。不，不是那里。这就是了。
Put that inside. No, not there. That's it.
等等，这是新的。请确保不要撞到它。
Wait! That's new.
Make sure not to bump it.
- 是的，就是这样。- 你在做什么？
- Yes, that's it.
- What are you doing?
哦，徐医生。你只是来上班的吗？
Oh, Dr. Seo. Are you just coming to work?
今天将有一位新的CT外科研究员加入我们。
A new CT surgical fellow
will be joining us today.
我一直在为他们重新安排。
I've been rearranging for them.
车恩才要搬到这个房间吗？
Is Cha Eunjae moving to this room?
这是正确的。从现在起，普通外科医生将在一个房间里、
That's right. From now on,
general surgeons will be in one room,
和CT外科医生将在另一个地方。
and CT surgeons will be in another.
你将与自己的专业。
You will be with your own specialty.
但是，为什么有三张桌子？
But, why are there three desks?
我不确定。朴民国主任让我再准备一份。
I'm not sure. Director Park Minguk
asked me to prepare another.
无论如何，我不敢相信我能够目睹这一景象。
Anyway, I can't believe
I get to witness this sight.
仿佛就在昨天，我们还在管理医院，只有金师傅。
It seems only yesterday
we ran the hospital with just Master Kim.
说实话，当姜东柱博士和尹瑞亭博士加入我们时、
Honestly, when Dr. Kang Dongju
and Dr. Yoon Seojeong joined us,
我从来没有想过，金师傅的梦想会实现。
I never imagined that Master Kim's dream
would come true.
但有一个房间却挤满了普通外科医生、
But one room is overflowing
with general surgeons,
而另一个房间里都是心胸外科医生。
and another room is full
of cardiothoracic surgeons.
在此基础上，创伤中心高高在上。
On top of that,
the Trauma Center is standing tall.
我被深深地感动了。
I am so deeply moved.
嘿，有个人在说话。
Hey, a man is talking.
天哪，他怎么会如此缺乏社交技巧？
Gosh, how could he be so lacking
in social skills?
我的天啊!对不起，别太在意。
My goodness! Sorry, go easy on that.
嘿，你来了。
Hey, you're here.
- 你整晚都在工作吗？- 当然了。
- Did you work all night?
- Of course.
我是待命的。当然，我整晚都在工作。
I was on call.
Of course I worked all night.
我一晚上都睡不着。
I couldn't sleep a wink.
你刚才不是在睡觉吗？
Weren't you sleeping just now?
睡觉？谁？
Sleeping? Who?
我没有睡觉。
I wasn't sleeping.
我给你带来了一些西红柿汁。
I brought you some tomato juice.
我在混合前把它们焯了一下。
I blanched them
before blending it.
味道应该还可以。
It should taste okay.
你自己做的？
You made it yourself?
- 你甚至把它们焯过水？- 是的。
- You even blanched them?
- Yes.
我甚至还亲自给它们焯水。
I even blanched them myself.
嘿，这是什么？
Hey, what is this?
你只用了几个西红柿就很动人。
You're quite moving
with just a few tomatoes.
当你在这时，也为我打开盖子。求你了？
While you're at it,
open the lid for me too. Please?
漂亮吗？
Pretty please?
对不起，我还在半梦半醒之间。
Sorry, I'm still half asleep.
我的舌头还没有完全醒过来。
My tongue isn't completely awake yet.
嗯!
Mmm!
这个味道不错。它是如此新鲜。
This tastes good. It's so fresh.
请忘记你刚才听到的内容。你能做到这一点吗？
Please forget what you just heard.
Can you do that?
不，我不能。
No, I can't.
这是我一时的错误，因为我很累。
It was a momentary error
on my part because I was tired.
请忘记它，好吗？
Please forget about it, okay?
我不想这样做。
I don't want to.
"漂亮的请。"
"Pretty please."
你又来了。
There you go again.
这个人将持续一段时间。什么？"请漂亮点"？
This one will last a while.
What? "Pretty please?"
别说了，徐宇镇。
Stop it, Seo Woojin.
- "漂亮吗？"- 嘿。
- "Pretty please?"
- Hey.
- 漂亮...- 嘘嘘。
- Pretty...
- Hush.
- 有人可能会听到。- 好吧，我不说了。
- Someone might hear.
- Okay, I'll stop.
- 但 "漂亮的请"？好吧，我不说了。- 认真地说，我说了停。
- But "pretty please?" Okay, I'll stop.
- Seriously, I said stop.
李承恩医生。这位是普通外科的徐武进医生。
Dr. Lee Seonung.
This is Dr. Seo Woojin in general surgery.
你好。我们上次在船上见过面。
Hello. We met on the boat last time.
哦，你一定是新的CT外科研究员。
Oh, you must be the new CT surgery fellow.
我是李璇。
I'm Lee Seonung.
从今天起，我将在道达姆医院报到。
As of today, I'm reporting to duty
at Doldam Hospital.
金师傅雇用了我。
Master Kim hired me.
很高兴见到你。我希望我们能相处愉快。
It's good to see you. I hope we get along.
请漂亮点。
Pretty please.
什么？
What?
这是一个来自急诊室的电话。
It's a call from the ER.
回头见，车恩杰博士。
See you later, Dr. Cha Eunjae.
祝你有个愉快的一天。
Have a good day.
他刚才说什么了？
What did he just say?
哦，别管他。
Oh, don't mind him.
他有时就是这样。他甚至一点都不好笑，但他努力了。
He's just like that sometimes.
He's not even funny, but he tries.
但他一点都不好笑，对吗？
But he's not funny at all, right?
天哪，说真的。
Gosh, seriously.
你喜欢番茄汁吗？
Do you like tomato juice?
是的。
Yes.
我们有什么？
What do we have?
他是国家跳台滑雪队的成员。他在落地时受伤。
He's on the national ski jump team.
He was injured while landing.
裴文静医生正在查看他的膝关节韧带。
Dr. Bae Munjeong
is looking at his knee ligaments.
但他一直说他有胃痛。
But he keeps saying he has stomach pain.
- CT怎么办？- CT...
- What about the CT?
- The CT…
CT显示前腹部的一部分有壁增强。
The CT shows wall enhancement
in a part of the front abdomen.
我想我们需要做一个手术观察。
I think we need to do
a surgical observation.
- 就在这里？- 是的。
- Right here?
- Yes.
但在后面，通气性看起来很好，尺寸也很小。
But in the back, the aeration looks good
and the size is small.
我认为增强的原因只是因为肠子肿胀了。
I think the enhancement is
just from the swollen bowels.
这是真的，但是...
That's true, but…
- 腹泻怎么办？- 没有。
- What about diarrhea?
- There is none.
- 他的化验结果如何？- 他的白细胞是9,000。
- What about his labs?
- His WBC is 9,000.
只有他的CRP略有升高。
Only his CRP is slightly elevated.
身体状况？
Physical condition?
RLQ里有一些温柔的东西。
There's some tenderness in the RLQ.
而且没有反弹？
And there's no rebound?
这并不突出。
It's not prominent.
它要么在那里，要么不在。
It's either there or not.
你说的不突出是什么意思？
What do you mean by not prominent?
病人一直说它很疼。
The patient keeps saying it hurts.
- 病人在哪里？- 在混合手术室。
- Where is the patient?
- In the hybrid OR.
膝关节韧带没有任何问题。
There's nothing wrong
with the knee ligaments.
对，我也说过同样的话、
Right, I said the same thing,
但病人一直说它很疼。
but the patient keeps saying
that it hurts.
请原谅我。
Excuse me.
他在三年前做了十字韧带手术。
He had surgery on his ACL three years ago.
哦，但现在看起来很好。
Oh, but it seems fine now.
我的胃痛得厉害。
My stomach hurts so much.
哦，我的胃。它正在杀害我。
Oh, my stomach. It's killing me.
让我看一下。
Let me take a look.
嘿，徐医生。你来了。
Hey, Dr. Seo. You're here.
病人一直抱怨胃痛。
The patient keeps complaining
about stomach pain.
但在CT扫描中并没有什么特别的东西。
But there isn't anything in particular
in the CT scan.
先生，请原谅我离开一下。
Sir, excuse me for a minute.
把你的膝盖抬起来。
Bring your knee up.
- 如果我按这里，会不会很疼？- 是的。
- Does it hurt if I press here?
- Yes.
这一边呢？
What about this side?
右边还疼吗？
Does the right side still hurt?
是的，确实如此。
Yes, it does.
让我看看你的衣服下面。
Let me look under your clothes.
如果我像这样点击它呢？
What if I tap on it like this?
这也很伤人。
That hurts too.
你能用点力气咳嗽吗？
Can you cough with some force?
你是否感到胃里有响声？
Do you feel a ringing in your stomach?
是的，我感觉到了。
Yes, I feel it.
让我们尝试一下不同的位置并进行比较。
Let's try a different position
and compare.
抬起你的腿。收紧你的肌肉。
Lift your legs. Tighten your muscles.
抬起你的头，看着你的膝盖。
Lift your head and look at your knees.
哪一个更伤人？早些时候还是现在？
Which one hurts more? Earlier or now?
这更让人伤心。
This hurts more.
好了，你现在可以放松了。
Okay. You can relax now.
张东华。
Jang Donghwa.
是吗？
Yes?
你检查过卡耐特的标志吗？
Did you check for Carnett's sign?
我做了...
I did…
那么你为什么建议进行手术观察？
Then why did you suggest
a surgical observation?
根本就没有肌肉的守护。
There's no muscle guarding at all.
请原谅我。怎么了？有什么不对吗？
Excuse me. What is it? Is something wrong?
这不是什么大事。这是一种常见的疾病
It's nothing big. It's a common illness
称为伪造。
called faking.
这是什么？
What is this?
你是故意在落地时摔倒的吗？
Did you fall while landing on purpose?
不，我没有。我真的很痛苦。
No, I didn't. I really am hurting.
你为什么不相信我？
Why won't you believe me?
骨科医生和我都同意。
The orthopedic surgeon and I agree.
考试结果没有任何问题。
There is nothing wrong
with the exam results.
真是一群庸医！"！
What a bunch of quacks!
如果考试成绩没有问题，是不是就没事了？
Is it all fine
if the exam results are fine?
我告诉你我很痛苦!
I'm telling you I'm in pain!
你这个可悲的傻瓜!
You pathetic fool!
比赛还有几天就开始了。这是什么？
The competition is days away.
What is this?
你浪费了我们的时间，在这个不吉利的时间里大惊小怪！
You wasted our time fussing over nothing,
at this ungodly hour!
我真的很痛苦!
I really was in pain!
忘了它吧，小混混！为什么，我应该把你撕碎。
Forget it, punk!
Why, I ought to rip you apart.
先生，你不能在这里这么大声说话......
Sir, you can't speak so loudly here...
你认为赢得一枚金牌是一个巨大的成就吗？
Do you think winning one gold medal
is a huge accomplishment?
你有吗？不要自以为是。
Do you? Don't flatter yourself.
明白了吗？
Got it?
勋章只是你生命中的一个小点。
A medal is just a tiny dot in your life.
你所做的只是在地图上放了一个点。
All you did was put a dot on the map.
你不是什么大人物。
You're no big shot.
你的傲慢是僵硬的，甚至不愿意练习。
You're stiff with arrogance
and won't even practice.
而现在，你假装受伤？
And now, you fake an injury?
你...
You…
你知道如果你因傲慢而变得过于僵硬会发生什么吗？
Do you know what happens
if you get too stiff with arrogance?
即使最轻微的错误也会导致巨大的伤害。
Even the slightest error
can lead to a huge injury.
明白了吗？
Got that?
一个人的生活也是如此。
A person's life is the same way.
朋克。
Punk.
天哪，我很抱歉。
Gosh, I'm sorry.
你在做什么？快起来吧！
What are you doing? Get up already!
天哪，那个教练真吓人。
Gosh, that coach is scary.
他肯定已经装了好几次了。
He must've faked it several times already.
让他走是对的吗？他说他很痛苦。
Is it right to let him go?
He says he's in pain.
尽管如此，我们也无能为力。
Still, there's nothing we can do.
我也是这么想的。我确信他们有队医。
That's what I think too.
I'm sure they have team doctors.
让我们尽我们所能吧，荣格医生。
Let's just do what we can, Dr. Jung.
好吧，如果OS和GS是这么说的。
Okay, if that's what OS and GS say.
我将暂时让他出院。
I'll discharge him for now.
请原谅我。
Excuse me.
关于赵善均先生...
About Mr. Cho Sungyoon…
我们不能给他打点滴，让他休息几个小时吗？
Couldn't we give him an IV
and let him rest for a few hours?
那是什么意思？
What does that mean?
压力也是一种类型的疾病。
Stress is a type of illness too.
经过几天的休息，他可以变得更好。
He could get better
with a few days of rest.
从什么时候开始，GS外科医生开始管理病人的压力水平？
Since when did GS surgeons
start to manage patients' stress levels?
什么？
Pardon?
没错，医生可以对病人产生同情心。
Right, a doctor can feel sympathetic
for a patient.
但这就是全部。
But that's all.
你告诉我做我必须做的事。
You told me to do what I had to do.
我的意思是你应该尽力做好你的工作。
I meant you should do your best
at your job.
你刚才所做的是过头了。
What you just did is go overboard.
不要把这两者混为一谈。
Don't confuse those two.
认真地说。
Seriously.
信息
INFORMATION
这一定是缺乏技巧，对吗？
It must be
a lack of finesse, right?
- 我是说徐医生。- 嗯。
- Dr. Seo, I mean.
- Mm.
我认为他说这些话是为了教导张博士、
I think he says what he says
to teach Dr. Jang,
但张博士似乎被他的话所伤。
but Dr. Jang seems to be hurt
by his words.
我觉得我在观察你的早期生活。
I feel like I'm watching you
in your early days.
天哪。
Gosh.
杨浩军不是负责居民的吗？
Wasn't Yang Hojun in charge
of the residents?
是的，他应该是这样的。
Yes, he was supposed to be.
我确信他把它传给了徐医生。
I'm sure he passed it on to Dr. Seo.
无论如何，他是世界上最好的
Anyway, he's the world's best
在无耻和没有责任感的情况下。
at being shameless
and having no sense of responsibility.
所以...
So…
你就不能理清这两者之间的关系吗？
can't you clear up some traffic
between those two?
天哪，别管他们了。
Gosh, leave them alone.
如果大人们为了这些事情而插手、
If grown-ups butt in
for these things,
它只会使事情变得更加复杂。
it will only make things more complicated.
他们需要对头，并为之结缘。
They need to butt heads and bond over it.
这就是他们成长的方式。
That's how they'll grow up.
张东华博士！
Dr. Jang Donghwa!
为金英九先生吸气。
Suction for Mr. Kim Inguk.
在接下来的一个小时里，请密切关注这个病人。
Keep an eye on this patient
for the next hour.
他是一个有肠梗阻的糖尿病患者。
He's a diabetic
with an intestinal obstruction.
你应该如何进行肠道休息？
How should you do a bowel rest?
他不应该口服任何东西，给他输液。
He should take nothing by mouth
and give him an IV.
那是在他没有糖尿病的时候。
That's when he isn't diabetic.
一位糖尿病患者
A diabetic patient
可能会进入低血糖状态。
could go into hypoglycemia.
所以你应该给他提供TPN，而不仅仅是输液。
So you should give him TPN,
not just fluids.
哦，对了。
Oh, right.
如果我再发现你在医院里玩游戏、
If I catch you playing games
in the hospital again,
你要加两小时的班。
you'll work two hours of overtime.
如果你想的话，就试试吧。
Try it if you want to.
张东华
JANG DONGHWA
张医生，你查过明天的手术安排吗？
Dr. Jang, have you checked
tomorrow's surgery schedule?
我现在正在做。
I'm on it now.
认真地说。
Seriously.
昨天的腹部受伤病人的报告在哪里？
Where is the report
on yesterday's abdomen injury patient?
我现在就去做。
I'll do it now.
不要忘记在今天下午之前整理好病例报告。
Don't forget to organize
the case report by this afternoon.
是的，先生。
Yes, sir.
你累了吗？
Are you tired?
不，先生。
No, sir.
是的，有一点。
Yes, a bit.
这意味着你做得很好。
That means you're doing well.
给你。
Here you go.
是的，先生。
Yes, sir.
哦，你在这里。
Oh, there you are.
你做过手术吗？
Did you have surgery?
我有一些练习要做。
I had some practice to do.
我现在已经完成了。
I'm done now.
这很难，不是吗？
It's hard, isn't it?
嗯，这很好。
Well, it's fine.
别紧张。
Take it easy.
容易。
Easy.
我敢打赌，他并不了解。
I'm betting that
he didn't understand.
你认为是这样吗？
Do you think so?
即使对一个头脑冷静的人来说也是如此、
Even for a cool-headed man,
客观地看待自己并不是一件容易的事，金师傅。
being objective about himself
is not an easy thing, Master Kim.
顺便说一下，你说你想告诉我一些事情。
By the way,
you said you wanted to tell me something.
它是什么？
What is it?
什么？
What?
创伤中心的新负责人？
A new head of the Trauma Center?
谁？
Who?
好吧、
Well,
我也不确定这些传言是否属实。
I'm not sure
if the rumors are true either.
我听说车振文医生将来担任创伤中心的负责人。
I hear Dr. Cha Jinman will be coming
as head of the Trauma Center.
你说的车振文医生，是指...
By Dr. Cha Jinman, do you mean…
车恩才的父亲？
Cha Eunjae's dad?
是的。
Yes.
希望、爱、服务
HOPE, LOVE, SERVICE
行政办公室
ADMINISTRATIVE OFFICE
哇哦!
Wow!
多好啊。这真是太完美了!
How nice. This is perfect!
现在我有了一个新的小辈，伟大的事情正在发生。
Great things are happening
now that I have a new junior.
现在，CT外科医生正在接管多尔达姆医院。
Now, CT surgeons are
taking over Doldam Hospital.
让我们来扫荡董事会，好吗？
Let's sweep the board, okay?
我缺乏实践经验。我有很多东西要学。
I'm lacking in practical experience.
I have a lot to learn.
不要担心。不要紧张。
Don't worry. Don't be nervous.
如果你有任何问题，随时可以问我。
If you have any questions, ask me anytime.
如果你需要任何帮助，请向我求助。
And if you need any help, ask for it.
你很快就会明白的，但多丹这里的人都很好。
You'll catch on soon enough,
but everyone here at Doldam is nice.
嗯...
Well…
只是要注意GS中的杨浩军医生。他不是那么伟大。
Just watch out for Dr. Yang Hojun in GS.
He's not that great.
顺便说一下，为什么有三张桌子？
By the way, why are there three desks?
哦...
Oh…
我不确定。
I'm not sure.
不可能。
No way.
以他的技能和他的名字价值，这不是不可能的事。
With his skills and his name value,
it's not out of the question.
事实上，我们从中获得了很多，吴女士。
In fact,
we're gaining a lot from this, Ms. Oh.
难道又是朴局长干的？
Is it Director Park's doing again?
是的，对吗？他向你施压，让你这样做。
It is, right? He pressured you into this.
天哪。不，它不是。
Gosh. No, it isn't.
这一次他说了什么来达到自己的目的？
What did he say this time
to get his own way?
他有没有利用开幕式的日期来对付你？或紧急直升机？
Did he use the opening date against you?
Or the emergency helicopter?
他用了什么样的借口
What kind of excuse did he use
来窃取创伤中心负责人的职位？
to steal the position of
head of the Trauma Center?
我没有从他那里偷来，吴女士。
I didn't steal it from him, Ms. Oh.
我从外面听到了你的声音。
I heard your voice from outside.
我不是故意的，但我无意中听到了你们的谈话。
I didn't mean to,
but I overheard your conversation.
我很高兴你已经听到了我的话。
I'm glad you already heard me.
当面告诉我。
Tell me in person.
你隐藏着什么样的情节
What kind of plot are you hiding
这个荒谬的人事任命背后是什么？
behind this ridiculous
personnel appointment?
没有任何情节。
There is no plot.
我很难过，吴女士。
I'm upset, Ms. Oh.
在过去的三年里，我一直以忠诚和真诚的态度工作。
I've been working with loyalty
and sincerity over the past three years.
这不是太荒唐的决定了，称之为忠诚和真诚吗？
Isn't this too absurd of a decision
to call it loyalty and sincerity?
你怎么能用那个万能的位置来做这件事呢？
How could you do that with
that position of all things?
你是如何培养这种随机和无意义的创造力的？
How do you develop such random
and senseless creativity?
我告诉你这是我的主意。
I told you it was my idea.
这就是我的意思!这是金师傅的主意...
That's what I mean!
It was Master Kim's idea…
- 什么 我说我们应该这样做。
- What?
- I said we should do it.
- 但是......--明国：看。
- But…
- MINGUK: Look.
我们以后再来澄清这个误解吧。
Let's clear up the misunderstanding later.
我们现在先到我的办公室去吧。
Let's go up to my office for now.
车金满教授刚到。
Professor Cha Jinman just arrived.
我们就这么做吧。
Let's do that.
后来。
Later.
- 我们以后再谈吧，吴女士 但是......。
- Let's talk later, Ms. Oh.
- But…
- 我们走吧。- 好的。
- Let's go.
- Okay.
但为什么呢？
But why?
究竟为什么？
Why on earth?
那我就不打扰你们了。
Then I'll leave you to talk.
我非常感谢你能来这里，查教授。
I'm so grateful to have you here,
Professor Cha.
欢迎。
Welcome.
在这里。
Here.
我已经想出了一份加入创伤中心的医生名单。
I've come up with a list of doctors
to join the Trauma Center.
啊，是的。
Ah, yes.
其中有几个人给了我积极的回应。
A few of them have given me
positive responses.
多尔达姆医院创伤中心推荐医生名单
DOLDAM HOSPITAL TRAUMA CENTER
RECOMMENDED DOCTOR LIST
多尔达姆的外科医生不在这里。
The Doldam surgeons aren't on here.
我还没能确认他们的技能。
I haven't been able
to confirm their skills yet.
你不需要担心这个问题。
You don't have to worry
about that.
多尔达姆外科医生的专长是治疗创伤病人。
The Doldam surgeons' specialty
is treating trauma patients.
金师傅一直专注于这个领域
Master Kim has focused on that area
并训练他们成为一个好的团队。
and trained them to be a good team.
朴主任。
Director Park.
我评判人的标准
My standards of judging people
与卜永菊的情况完全不同。
is quite different from Bu Yongju's.
我的教学风格也应大不相同。
My style of teaching
should differ greatly as well.
不可能。
No way.
你的意思不是说你会因为我而把外科医生排除在多德姆之外，对吗？
You don't mean you will exclude surgeons
from Doldam because of me, right?
我的意思是我们不能给多丹的外科医生任何特殊待遇。
I mean we can't give Doldam surgeons
any special treatment.
这个中心靠政府资助运行。
This center runs on government funding.
规则必须是公平的。
The rules must be fair.
此外，技能可能对治疗创伤很重要、
Besides, skill may be important
in treating trauma,
但团队合作也是如此。
but so is teamwork.
你说你会根据技能进行公平判断。
You said you'd judge fairly
based on skill.
但在我听来，你会有非常个人的标准。
But it sounds to me that you will have
very personal standards.
说实话，如果他们向你学习，他们会怎么样是很明显的。
To be honest, it's obvious
how they'd be if they learned from you.
他们将是鲁莽的，无礼的、
They will be reckless, insolent,
或出于傲慢而乐于挥舞手术刀。
or happy to wield a scalpel
out of arrogance.
像这样的人。
People like that.
你喜欢这样的孩子。
You like kids like that.
我确实赞成那些为病人做他们必须做的事情的医生。
I do favor doctors
who do what they must for patients.
如果他们有一双好手，那就更好了。
And if they have good hands, even better.
好手并不总是能成为好医生。
A good hand doesn't always
make a good doctor.
正是如此。
Exactly.
就像好的考试成绩也不能成为好医生一样。
Just like how good test scores
don't make good doctors either.
嗯...
Well…
我认为我们现在不能就人事问题作出决定。
I don't think we can decide on
personnel matters right now.
你这么自信吗？
Are you so confident?
如果我没有信心、
If I weren't confident,
我是否会安排这次会议？
would I have set up this meeting?
我相信你知道，我的标准
I'm sure you know that my standards
是非常挑剔和保守的。
are very picky and conservative.
我确实记得，你的狭隘和固执让我感到沮丧。
I do remember that you frustrated me with
your narrow-minded and stubborn nature.
好吧，在创伤中心开放之前，我们仍有一些时间。
Well, we still have some time
until the Trauma Center opens.
所以，在适当的时候...
So, in due time…
那么，我们就来吧。
Let's do it, then.
让我们看看多尔丹的外科医生有多厉害。
Let's see how good Doldam's surgeons are.
如果你自己操作，效果会更好。
It would be better
if you operate yourself.
我想看看你有多好，因为已经过去这么久了。
I want to see how good you are
since it's been so long.
我想知道这些年来你的技能有多大的提高。
I wonder how much your skills
have improved over the years.
- 你不是在喝这个，是吗？- 金师傅。
- You're not drinking this, are you?
- Master Kim.
我想知道
I wonder
如果你已经生疏了。
if you've gotten rusty at all.
让我们在适当的时候讨论人事问题。
Let's discuss personnel matters
in due time.
我带你看看你将使用的房间，查教授。
I'll show you the room
that you will be using, Professor Cha.
房间？
Room?
我给你指路。
I'll show you the way.
我们走吧。
Let's go.
查教授？
Professor Cha?
你真的会好起来吗？
Will you really be okay?
不要问。
Don't ask.
我只是为这个决定后悔了大约三秒钟。
I was just regretting this decision
for about three seconds.
他还没有签署合同。
He hasn't signed the contract yet.
如果你改变了主意，现在告诉我还不算太晚。
It's not too late to tell me
if you've changed your mind.
我们不能在打开门之前就结束事情。
We can't end things
before we even open the door.
所以最终，你真的会进入这扇窄门？
So ultimately,
you really will enter this narrow door?
如果你拿起一把剑、
If you pick up a sword,
至少你可以做的是拔掉它的剑鞘。
the least you can do is unsheathe it.
好的。
Okay.
记住。那是我给你的最后机会。
Remember.
That was the last chance I gave you.
当我第一次在创伤中心看到你时、
When I first saw you
in the Trauma Center,
你就像复仇者联盟。
you were like the Avengers.
- 认真的。- 复仇者联盟？别奉承我了。
- Seriously.
- The Avengers? Don't flatter me.
总之，我很荣幸能与你合作。
Anyway,
I'm honored to work with you.
获得荣誉？
Honored?
李博士，你用了这么甜蜜的字眼。你很荣幸。
Dr. Lee, you use such sweet words.
You're honored.
我真的觉得你很了不起。
I really think you're impressive.
完全可以理解。我知道我们这些外科医生都很厉害。
Totally understandable.
I know we surgeons are pretty impressive.
嗯!
Mmm!
李博士，你是我们的幸运符。
Dr. Lee, you're our lucky charm.
这是你自己调配的吗？天哪。
Did you blend this yourself? Gosh.
我没有做，但它很好，对吗？
I didn't make it, but it's good, right?
嗯!
Mmm!
怎么了，徐医生？
What is it, Dr. Seo?
这里是CS室。进来之前请敲门。
This is the CS room.
Knock before you come in.
李博士。
Dr. Lee.
你去过急诊室了吗？
Have you been to the ER yet?
你想四处看看，跟急诊室的人打个招呼吗？
Do you want to look around
and say hi to the ER folks?
为什么？你有什么要告诉我吗，徐医生？
Why? Do you have something
to tell me, Dr. Seo?
你不觉得你有事情要告诉我吗，查医生？
Don't you think you have something
to tell me, Dr. Cha?
后来。
Later.
我们以后再谈吧。
Let's talk later.
我现在和李博士有事情要做。
I have something to do
with Dr. Lee right now.
李博士，你能让我们在房间里待一会儿吗？
Dr. Lee, could you give us the room
for a moment?
我有事情要和查医生讨论。
I have something to discuss with Dr. Cha.
是的，当然了。
Yes, of course.
不，李博士！
No, Dr. Lee!
- 没有必要离开。- 好的。
- There's no need to leave.
- Okay.
我只需要5分钟，李博士。
I just need five minutes, Dr. Lee.
哦，好的。
Oh, okay.
李医生，你只需要听一个CT外科医生同行的话。
Dr. Lee, you only need to listen
to a fellow CT surgeon.
李博士。
Dr. Lee.
来吧，我肯定你听错了什么。
Come on, I'm sure you misheard something.
所有地方中的创伤中心？那个地方就是金师傅的...
The Trauma Center of all places?
That place is Master Kim's...
我是听金师傅自己说的。
I heard it from Master Kim himself.
我知道。那么主人......什么？
I know. So Master… What?
他为什么突然做出这个决定？
Why did he make that decision
all of a sudden?
如果朴主任不给他压力、
If Director Park didn't pressure him,
并且他自己做出了这个决定、
and he made this decision himself,
这更是一个谜。
it's even more of a mystery.
也许、
Perhaps,
会不会是因为他的多发性硬化症？
could it be because
of his multiple sclerosis?
他的症状可能在我们不知道的情况下变得更糟。
His symptoms might have gotten worse
without our knowing.
来吧，不可能的。
Come on, there's no way.
他在休息日一直去钓鱼、
He's been going fishing on his days off,
获得大量的新鲜空气和运动。
getting plenty of fresh air and exercise.
他一直在努力工作以保持健康。
He's been working hard
to keep up his health.
对，当我们上个月做了一些血检和其他一些测试、
Right, when we did some bloodwork
and a few other tests last month,
他的所有结果都没有问题。
all his results were okay.
对，我怀疑是这样的，吴女士。
Right, I doubt that's what it is, Ms. Oh.
如果不是这样，我就是完全不明白。
If that's not it,
I just don't understand it at all.
你在这里做什么？
What are you doing here?
我需要一个解释，先生。
I need an explanation, sir.
什么？
What?
天哪。
Gosh.
首先，金师傅。
First of all, Master Kim.
车金满作为创伤中心的负责人？
Cha Jinman as head of the Trauma Center?
是否有
Is there
其他一些我们不知道的原因？
some other reason that we don't know of?
如果不是，我就是不明白。
If not, I just don't get it.
不，吴女士。
No, Ms. Oh.
这个职位应该向任何有能力的人开放、
That position should be open
to anyone capable,
即使那不是我。
even if that isn't me.
说你不能理解
Saying that
you can't understand that
是一个危险的想法。
is a dangerous thought.
我知道。
I know.
我们都在为创伤中心的工作而努力。
We've all been working very hard
for the Trauma Center.
如果不是因为你的努力和奉献、
And if not
for your efforts and dedication,
我们就不会走到这一步。
we wouldn't have gotten this far.
但努力和献身精神
But effort and dedication
应该在你给他们的那一刻就留下。
should be left behind
the moment you've given them.
希望得到某种形式的付款
Hoping for some kind of payment
或要求承认你的投入、
or demanding recognition of your input,
事情会在瞬间变成一团泥泞。
things will turn into
a muddy mess in a flash.
但是、
But,
创伤中心的负责人应该是负责任的领导。
the head of the Trauma Center
should be the leader who will take charge.
这个职位应该被填补
That position should be filled
经过更仔细和缜密的考虑。
after more careful
and meticulous consideration.
如果你们所有人都继续努力工作
If all of you keep working hard
在你们各自的岗位上、
in your respective positions,
不会因为我们雇了人就发生什么大的变化。
nothing drastic will happen
just because we hired someone
从外面来，成为创伤中心的新负责人。
from the outside
to be the new head of the Trauma Center.
我的天啊。
My goodness.
我知道。
I know.
这对我们来说也将是一个考验。
This will be a test for us too.
然而、
However,
我们一开业就会有更多的外伤病人、
we will have more trauma patients
once we open,
那么我们就需要更多的医生。
then we'll need more doctors.
不接受新医生、
Without accepting new doctors,
你认为我们能坚持多久？
how much longer do you think
we can hold out?
因此，请、
So please,
接受我的决定，不要有任何偏见。
accept my decision without any bias.
好的，吴女士？
Okay, Ms. Oh?
杜尔。
Doil.
张主任和裴医生也是如此。
Chief Jang and Dr. Bae too.
好的。
Okay.
郑博士和恩塔克也是如此。
Dr. Jung and Euntak too.
你呢，徐宇镇医生？
And you, Dr. Seo Woojin?
发生了什么事？
What's going on?
在创伤中心准备好之前，我将与你分享这个办公室。
I'll be sharing this office with you
until the Trauma Center is ready.
我在问你为什么来多丹医院。
I'm asking why you came
to Doldam Hospital.
朴主任为我提供了创伤中心负责人的职位、
Director Park offered me the position
of the head of the Trauma Center,
而我接受了。
and I accepted.
爸爸！
Dad!
你在医院里叫我爸爸可以吗？
Is it okay for you to call me Dad
in the hospital?
如果你是创伤中心的负责人，那金师傅呢？
If you're the head of the Trauma Center,
what about Master Kim?
我是说，你为什么要辞去大学医院的工作？
I mean, why did you quit your job
at the university hospital?
为了什么？
What for?
我从今天的社会中得到了很多特权。
I've received much privilege
from today's society.
什么？
What?
由于这一点，我获得了荣誉，也受到了关注。
Thanks to that, I've received honor
and been in the limelight.
现在是我回报的时候了。
It's time for me to pay it back.
对社会而言、
For society,
我打算从这里开始承担起责任，履行我的职责。
I intend to take on responsibility
and perform my duties from here.
- 爸爸。- 而最重要的是、
- Dad.
- And most of all,
我也想见见你。
I wanted to see you too.
我很抱歉，先生、
I'm sorry, sir,
但我不能同意你这次的决定。
but I can't agree
with your decision this time.
为什么不呢？你还需要更多的解释吗？
Why not? Do you still need
more of an explanation?
不，我理解你所说的一切。
No, I understood everything you said.
我只是...
I just…
不能同意它。这就是全部。
can't agree with it. That's all.
我告诉过你。你不需要像这样保持警惕。
I told you. You don't need to keep
your guard up like that.
车振满教授是一位有经验的天才外科医生。
Professor Cha Jinman is a talented surgeon
who has experience in the field.
而有了这个机会、
And with this opportunity,
从局外人那里得到一个客观的评价不会是个坏主意。
it won't be a bad idea to get
an objective evaluation from an outsider.
你是唯一能评价我这个医生的人。
You're the only one
who can evaluate me as a doctor.
你也是唯一一个我想被承认为医生的人。
You're also the only one
I want to be recognized by as a doctor.
嘿，Woojin。
Hey, Woojin.
我不希望创伤中心没有你。
I don't want a trauma center without you.
如果你决定留在这里、
If you decide to stay here,
我也会。
I will too.
我们可以谈一谈吗？
Can we talk for a minute?
所以...
So…
我的父亲将来到多尔丹医院。
My dad will be coming to Doldam Hospital.
我从金师傅那里听说了。
I heard from Master Kim.
哦，我明白了。
Oh, I see.
它是什么？
What is it?
嗯？
Hm?
你有话要对我说。告诉我。
You have something
you want to say to me. Tell me.
嗯，问题是...
Well, the thing is…
我爸爸说他还没有找到住的地方，所以...
My dad says he hasn't found
a place to stay yet, so…
对不起，我们该怎么做？
Sorry, what do we do?
我所有的东西怎么办？
What about all my stuff?
我们还没有拆开它们，所以它们还在箱子里。
We haven't unpacked them,
so they're still in boxes.
如果我说我有一个室友，他就不会进你的房间。
If I say that I have a roommate,
he won't go into your room.
在他几天后找到地方之前，能不能请你住在别的地方？
Could you please stay somewhere else
until he finds a place in a few days?
我研究了一下，但公司的住房已经满了。
I looked into it,
but company housing is already full.
他说他要睡在一家旅馆里、
He said he would sleep at an inn,
但他必须一路走到镇上。
but he'd have to go all the way into town.
我有一年没见到他了，所以我没有感到安心。
I haven't seen him in a year,
so I didn't feel at ease.
好吧，我就留在医院里。
Okay, I'll stay at the hospital.
你没有生气，是吗？
You're not mad, are you?
一点也不。
Not at all.
谢谢。
Thanks.
- Eunjae。- 是吗？
- Eunjae.
- Yes?
他是你的父亲。
He's your dad.
而我是你的男人。
And I'm your man.
对你来说，问我也不必这么难，好吗？
It doesn't have to be so hard
for you to ask me, okay?
好的。
Okay.
不要被抓。
Don't get caught.
好吧，我不说了。
Okay, I won't.
对番茄汁的事感到抱歉。
Sorry about the tomato juice.
嘿，那个西红柿汁...
Hey, that tomato juice…
好的。
Okay.
抵达多伦多医院教授公园
ARRIVED AT DOLDAMN HOSPITAL
PROFESSOR PARK
一般来说，重要的是要把它做得很好。
Generally speaking,
it's important to make it down well.
但这个该死的东西叫作自豪感
But this darn thing called pride
使得一个人表现得很小气。
makes a man act petty.
- 他为什么要这样做？- 你在哪里？
- Why did he do that?
- Where are you?
- 他在想什么？- 他在哪里？
- What was he thinking?
- Where is he?
我们来了!
We're coming!
- 快点！- 湘云！
- Hurry up!
- Sungyoon!
- 我认为这很严重。- 快点。
- I think it's serious.
- Hurry.
嘿，桑琼。
Hey, Sungyoon.
- 你还好吗？- 他的腿断了！
- Are you okay?
- His leg is broken!
这种方式。
This way.
- 湘云！- 教练！
- Sungyoon!
- Coach!
教练!
Coach!
- 快点！- 我们必须帮助他！
- Hurry up!
- We have to help him!
- 快点！- 哦，不。
- Hurry!
- Oh, no.
快点！教练！
Hurry! Coach!
- 忍受吧。- 嘿，你打了911吗？
- Endure it.
- Hey, did you call 911?
不要碰他。
Don't touch him.
你好，我在这里。
Hello, I'm here.
嗯？
Huh?
嘿，郑博士。我在这里。
Hey, Dr. Jung. I'm here.
嘿，尹阿雷姆博士。
Hey, Dr. Yoon Areum.
那么好吧。
All right then.
嗯？
Hm?
无论如何，这是金师傅的决定。
Anyway,
it was Master Kim's decision.
查博士究竟是个什么样的人？
What kind of person is Dr. Cha exactly?
嗯，他在心胸外科方面相当有名。
Well, he was pretty well-known
in cardiothoracic surgery.
嗯？
Huh?
尹医生。你来的真早。你今晚不是在值班吗？
Dr. Yoon. You're here early.
Aren't you on call tonight?
我有一些文件要看。但是，裴医生。
I had some papers to look over.
But, Dr. Bae.
医院里的气氛怎么了？
What's with the mood in the hospital?
哦。
Oh.
天哪，金师傅刚才引爆了一个巨大的炸弹。
Gosh, Master Kim set off
a massive bomb just now.
五...
Five…
我可以帮你什么吗？
Can I help you with anything?
你在这里。
You're here.
我听到了。
I heard.
显然，金师傅今天引爆了一枚核弹。
Apparently, Master Kim set off
a nuclear bomb today.
我知道。
I know.
他做到了。
He did.
我们该怎么做？感觉每个人都在精神崩溃。
What do we do? It feels like everyone
is having a mental breakdown.
你还好吗，恩塔克？
Are you okay, Euntak?
这对我来说也是一种崩溃。
It was a breakdown for me too.
但在听到金师傅的解释后、
But after hearing
Master Kim's explanation,
我理解他为什么要这样做。
I understood why he did what he did.
这一直是问题所在。
That's always the problem.
每当金师傅引爆炸弹、
Whenever Master Kim sets off a bomb,
你想，"这有什么意义吗？"
you think, "Does this make any sense?"
但是，当你听他说完后，你总是能理解他。
But then when you hear him out,
you always understand him.
你有没有倒过时差？
Are you jet-lagged at all?
我很好。我在两天内就调整好了。
I'm fine. I adjusted within two days.
哦，对了。
Oh, right.
在这里。
Here.
我在回来的路上在机场买的。
I bought it at the airport on my way back.
我错过了把它交给你的机会。
I missed the chance to give it to you.
因为你的手很珍贵。
Since your hands are precious.
我很想念你。
I missed you.
我们只分开了一个星期。
We were only apart for a week.
但你怎么能
But how could you
甚至不给我发一次短信？
not even text me once?
你去一个偏远地区做志愿者。
You went to volunteer in a remote area.
"我想你。"
"I miss you."
"你什么时候回来？"
"When are you coming back?"
"尽快回来。"
"Come back soon."
我看起来像是在发脾气。
I'd seem like I was throwing a fit.
这一直是问题所在。
That's always the problem.
你想，"这有什么意义吗？"
You think, "Does this make any sense?"
但是，当我听你说完、
But when I hear you out,
我总是理解你。
I always understand you.
嗯!
Mm!
你说你想念我。
You said you missed me.
我想看看你有多想念我。
I want to check how much you missed me.
嗯!
Mm!
我们在医院里，尹医生。
We're in the hospital, Dr. Yoon.
看到了吗？你并没有那么想我。
See? You didn't miss me that much.
现在还剩下40分钟。
There are still 40 minutes left.
什么？
What?
直到你下班。
Until you get off work.
尽管如此，我们今天下午的病人并不多。
Still, we didn't have
very many patients this afternoon.
张博士。
Dr. Jang.
什么？
What?
我做错了什么吗？
Did I do something wrong?
它是什么？
What is it?
是的，道达姆医院急诊室？
Yes, Doldam Hospital ER?
是的。
Yes.
是的，知道了。
Yes, got it.
有人在滑雪时摔倒了。他们将在5分钟内到达这里。
Someone fell while skiing.
They'll be here in five minutes.
什么？
What?
这让我很抓狂。
This is driving me nuts.
我们祝你健康
WE WISH YOU GOOD HEALTH
是什么样的病人？
What kind of patient is it?
有人在滑雪时又摔倒了。
Someone fell while skiing again.
我们被告知这是个开放性骨折。
We were told it was an open fracture.
下个月，在平昌将有一场世界锦标赛的比赛。
Next month, there's going to be
a World Championship game in Pyeongchang.
我们可能会继续看到那些在训练中受伤的病人。
We'll probably keep seeing patients
who get injured while training.
急诊病人!
Emergency patient!
- 湘云。- 嘿，坚持住。
- Sungyoon.
- Hey, hang in there.
- 湘云！- 我们在医院里。
- Sungyoon!
- We're at the hospital.
真是一群庸医！"！
What a bunch of quacks!
如果考试成绩没有问题，是不是就没事了？
Is it all fine
if the exam results are fine?
我告诉你我很痛苦!
I'm telling you I'm in pain!
什么？
What?
为混合动力车干杯!现在!
To the hybrid OR! Now!
请。
Please.
这种方式。
This way.
- 中间的床！- 这边走！
- The middle bed!
- This way!
先生。
Sir.
- 要小心。- 请在外面等候。
- Be careful.
- Please wait outside.
徐博士！
Dr. Seo!
- 先生！- 这是他的腿。
- Sir!
- It's his leg.
让我们把他抬起来。一，二。
Let's lift him up. One, two.
要小心。
Be careful.
好的。
Okay.
就一秒钟，爸爸。一秒钟。
Just a second, Dad. One second.
一秒钟...
One second…
等一下，爸爸！
Just a second, Dad!
请稍等。
Just a second.
这是我洗的衣服。
It's my laundry.
请稍等。
Just a second.
进来吧，爸爸。
Come in, Dad.
这很好，很舒适。
It's nice and cozy.
你一个人住在这里吗？
Do you live here alone?
不，我有一个室友。
No, I have a roommate.
我提到你要来，所以我的朋友就住在医院里。
I mentioned you were coming,
so my friend is staying at the hospital.
医院？
The hospital?
你的室友是个医生？
Your roommate is a doctor?
什么？
What?
是的，嗯...
Yes, well…
我是道达姆医院的尹阿鲁姆医生。
It's Dr. Yoon Areum at Doldam Hospital.
她是一名急诊科医生。
She's an emergency medicine doctor.
我的房间在这边。你可以把你的东西放在这里。
My room is this way.
You can leave your stuff here.
我会做的。
I'll do it.
启动两条静脉输液管，并开始用500cc温盐水进行水化。
Start two IV lines, and start
hydration with 500cc of warm saline.
获得两个紧急包RBC。
Get two emergency pack RBCs.
并准备10个RBC和8个FFP。
And prepare ten RBCs and eight FFPs.
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
徐医生，你找到出血的病灶了吗？
Dr. Seo, have you found
the bleeding focus?
这是腹腔积血。
It's hemoperitoneum.
张东华，把那一边打开。
Jang Donghwa, open that side up.
彻底打开它!
Open it up all the way!
这是他的脾脏。
It's his spleen.
荣格医生，血压是80，超过40。
Dr. Jung, BP is 80 over 40.
- 准备好RIS!- 是的，医生。
- Prepare the RIS!
- Yes, Doctor.
Areum，让实验室开始工作。
Areum, get the labs started.
好的，我去准备。
Okay, I'll get it ready.
他的脉搏真的很弱。
His pulse is really weak.
他可能也有血管损伤。
He might have a vessel injury too.
腘窝动脉？
The popliteal artery?
是的，这可能是。
Yes, it could be.
是否有任何抽水？
Was there any pumping?
不，现场没有任何东西。
No, there wasn't any at the scene.
Eom女士，请南博士开一个手术室。
Ms. Eom, ask Dr. Nam to open up an OR.
- 并叫车恩杰医生。- 是的，医生。
- And call Dr. Cha Eunjae.
- Yes, Doctor.
让我们在这里安装一个临时夹板。
Let's get a temporary splint on here.
- 郑博士，通过镇静剂看他。- 好的。
- Dr. Jung, see him through sedation.
- Okay.
恩塔克。
Euntak.
我会把它准备好。
I'll get it ready.
- 让我们给他插管。- 是的，医生。
- Let's get him intubated.
- Yes, Doctor.
张东华，你来协助。
Jang Donghwa, you assist.
什么？
What?
张东华，别磨磨蹭蹭了!
Jang Donghwa, stop dawdling!
穿上你的擦伤服。快点。
Get your scrubs on. Hurry.
请原谅我。即将通过。
Excuse me. Coming through.
发生了什么事？
What's going on?
是急诊病人吗？
Is it an emergency patient?
嗯，也许？我想是的。
Well, maybe? I think so.
让我们开始吧。手术刀。
Let's begin. Scalpel.
但是，先生，这里是急诊室。
But sir, this is the ER.
准备大量的纱布以备出血。
Prepare a lot of gauze
for the bleeding.
是的，医生。
Yes, Doctor.
博维。
Bovie.
吸力！大胶带!
Suction! Large tape!
理查德森。
Richardson.
镊子。
Forceps.
吸力。
Suction.
我说了，吸力!
I said, suction!
不要碰那个。你会压坏胰腺的。
Don't touch that.
You're crushing the pancreas.
哦，好的。
Oh, okay.
恩塔克，与张东华交换。
Euntak, switch with Jang Donghwa.
钳子。
Clamp.
这里还有一个。
Another one here.
请打领带。
Tie, please.
削减。
Cut.
另一个。
Another.
我们将暂时保留脾脏动脉、
We'll temporarily hold the splenic artery,
用纱布包好，做个CT，然后把他送到手术室。
pack it with gauze, get a CT,
and get him to the OR.
- 削减。- 削减。
- Cut.
- 给我一个封面。- 好的。
- Get me a cover.
- Okay.
我们正在转移病人。
We're moving the patient.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
你是来找乐子的吗？
Are you here to have fun?
你在做什么，只是站在旁边看吗？
What are you doing,
just standing around and watching?
我很抱歉，我当时被吓呆了。
I'm sorry, I was so dumbstruck.
迅速行动起来，跑到手术室去。
Get your act together fast
and run over to the OR.
我们马上就开始进行脾脏切除手术。
We're starting a splenectomy right away.
迅速做好准备。
Get ready quickly.
快行动起来吧!
Get a move on!
徐博士。
Dr. Seo.
张东华是一名第三年的居民。
Jang Donghwa is
a third-year resident.
你至少应该沿途解释一下。
You should at least explain things
along the way.
他必须知道自己在做什么才能跟上。
He has to know what he's doing
to follow along.
现在，病人是第一位的。
Right now, the patient comes first.
没有时间去关注张东华的心情。
There's no time
to look out for Jang Donghwa's mood.
你有什么问题？你表现得不像你自己。
What's wrong with you?
You're not acting like yourself.
你为什么这么着急呢？
Why are you in such a rush?
那个病人
That patient
是在国家队。
is on the national team.
那么？
So?
他是今天早上的那个病人
He's the patient from this morning
我把他送走了，因为他假装疼痛。
that I sent away for faking his pains.
你真的可以接受拉米亚吗？
Are you really okay with ramyeon?
我通常在外面吃饭或叫外卖。
I usually eat out or order in.
我没有意识到我已经没有米了。
I didn't realize I was out of rice.
外卖食品的味道也很好。
Delivery food tastes good too.
这很好。不要管我。
It's fine. Don't mind me.
我不是不喜欢拉米亚。
I don't dislike ramyeon.
嗯。
Mm.
是医院的问题吗？
Is it the hospital?
是的，他们认为是腘绳肌动脉断裂。
Yes. They think
it's a ruptured popliteal artery.
开始行动。
Get going.
完成后将碗留在水槽中即可。
Just leave the bowl in the sink
when you're done.
- 我回来后就洗碗。- 好的。
- I'll do the dishes when I get back.
- Okay.
手术可能会迟到，所以不要等了。
The surgery might run late,
so don't wait up.
好的。
Okay.
这是今天早上留下的西红柿。喝之前要摇匀。
IT'S THE TOMATOES LEFT FROM THIS MORNING.
SHAKE WELL BEFORE DRINKING.
女更衣室
WOMEN'S LOCKER ROOM
嘿，李博士。你还在这里吗？
Hey, Dr. Lee. Are you still here?
你要回家了吗？
Are you going home?
我回家后回来做了一个紧急手术。
I went home and came back
for an emergency surgery.
一个紧急手术？
An emergency surgery?
我也可以进入手术室吗？
May I also go into the OR?
它是什么？
What is it?
你能有多幸运？天哪。
How lucky can you get? Gosh.
这种罕见的情况究竟从何而来？
Where on earth did
this rarity come from?
快点准备好。
Hurry up and get ready.
我今天要给你一个教训。
I'll teach you a lesson today.
限制区手术室
RESTRICTED AREA
OPERATING ROOM
CT扫描似乎显示了损害
The CT scan seems to show damage
在胫骨前动脉和胫骨后动脉中
in the anterior
and posterior tibial artery
在远端区域而不是腘绳肌动脉。
in the distalis region
rather than the popliteal artery.
我们必须做一些探索、
We'll have to do some exploring,
但从我在戴夹板时看到的情况来看、
but from what I saw
while putting on the splints,
这似乎是深层的腓肠神经。
it seems to be the deep peroneal nerve.
Eunjae, 动脉吻合术怎么样了？
Eunjae, what about the artery anastomosis?
它周围有很多组织损伤、
There's a lot of tissue damage around it,
所以我正在考虑从另一侧进行GSV移植。
so I'm considering
a GSV graft from the other side.
为了防止隔间综合症、
In order to prevent
compartment syndrome,
宗庆后也在考虑做筋膜切除术。
Munjeong is considering
a fasciotomy as well.
你将如何处理腓肠神经？
What will you do about the peroneal nerve?
纱布。
Gauze.
好的，Bovie。
Okay. Bovie.
握住这里。
Hold here.
镊子。
Forceps.
梅岑鲍姆剪刀。
Metzenbaum scissors.
对不起，先生。
Sorry, sir.
移除脾脏。
Remove the spleen.
纱布，请。
Gauze, please.
缝合。
Suture.
让金师傅接电话。
Get Master Kim on the line.
主人、
Master,
我们将在5分钟内完成缝合工作。
we'll finish suturing in five.
我们会从神经外科开始吗？
Will we start with neurorrhaphy?
你在说什么？动脉是第一位的。
What are you saying?
The arteries come first.
他是国家队的一员。
He's on the national team.
如果我们不尽快缝合神经，他可能再也没有机会跳了。
If we don't stitch up the nerves soon,
he might never get to jump again.
如果我们不尽快解决他的动脉问题，他可能会失去整条腿。
If we don't get to his arteries soon,
he might lose his whole leg.
主人。
Master.
削减。
Cut.
张东华，你做闭合缝合。
Jang Donghwa, you do the closing sutures.
三分钟之内。
Within three minutes.
张博士。
Dr. Jang.
把它给我。
Give it to me.
主人。
Master.
我们不能先做神经切断术吗？
Can't we do the neurorrhaphy first?
徐武进。
Seo Woojin.
如此严重的骨折意味着受伤部位的末端被压碎了。
A fracture this serious means
the end of the injury site is crushed.
即使你在探索后做了神经外科手术、
Even if you do a neurorrhaphy
after exploring,
存活率太低。我们不能推迟动脉吻合术。
the viability is too low.
We can't delay the artery anastomosis.
如果他不能从神经损伤中恢复过来、
If he doesn't recover
from the nerve injury,
反正他的运动员生涯已经结束了。
his life as an athlete is over anyway.
不管怎么说，这都是对那个人的死刑判决。
Either way,
it's a death sentence for that man.
不过，宁可冒着风险、
Still, rather than taking a risk,
我认为先做动脉手术是正确的，徐医生。
I think it's right to do
the arterial surgery first, Dr. Seo.
神经在受到伤害的那一刻就开始死亡。
Nerves start to die
the moment they sustain an injury.
那么尽快把它们缝合起来不是最好的吗？
Then isn't it best to stitch them
back up as soon as possible?
金师傅。以你的速度，这是有可能的。
Master Kim.
With your speed, it's possible.
主人。
Master.
你为什么犹豫不决呢？
Why are you hesitating?
嗯？
Hm?
所有手术都必须以病人的生命为优先。
All surgeries must prioritize
the patient's life.
其次是病人的安全。
Next is the patient's safety.
关于功能的决定排在最后。
Decisions on function come last.
这里的每个人都知道这一点。
Everyone in here knows that.
那么你为什么要浪费时间呢？
So why are you wasting time?
你不是在思考
You're not thinking
像个疯子一样先做神经外科手术，你呢？
of doing a neurorrhaphy first
like a madman, are you?
我们正在考虑什么才是对这个病人最好的方法。
We're contemplating what would be
the best method for this patient.
那么你为什么要考虑这个问题呢？
So why are you contemplating that?
拯救他的命令已经确定。
The order to save him is already set.
对那个病人来说、
To that patient,
他作为运动员的生命也岌岌可危。
his life as an athlete
is also on the line.
如果你错过了操作的时机，他将失去作为运动员的生命。
If you miss the timing to operate,
he will lose his life as an athlete
以及他的腿。
as well as his leg.
或者，他可能不会失去任何一个。
Or, he might not lose either one.
好的，吴女士。
All right, Ms. Oh.
你能检查一下病人的左脚的肤色吗？
Could you check the complexion
of the patient's left foot?
看起来不错，金师傅。
It's looking good, Master Kim.
吴镇。你还需要多长时间才能完成关闭？
Woojin. How much longer do you need
to finish closing?
张东华博士。
Dr. Jang Donghwa.
我已经完成了。
I'm done.
- 削减。- 削减。
- Cut.
我们已经完成了关闭，金师傅。
We're done closing, Master Kim.
我们是先做动脉？还是做神经外科手术？
Are we doing the arteries first?
Or the neurorrhaphy?
先做神经外科手术。
Neurorrhaphy first.
好的，先做神经切断术。
Okay, the neurorrhaphy first.
你不应该从病人的角度去看。
You shouldn't look
at the patient's perspective.
你必须看一下症状，卜医生。
You must look at the symptoms, Dr. Bu.
这就是为什么我刚刚检查了他的症状。
That's why I just checked his symptoms.
你没听说他左脚的肤色恢复了吗？
Didn't you hear the complexion
in his left foot is back?
这意味着
That means
两条动脉中的一条还没有被损坏。而这意味着
one of the two arteries
hasn't been damaged. And that means
首先缝合神经不会有太大的风险。
it won't be too much of a risk
to stitch up the nerves first.
别这么外行。
Don't be such an amateur.
你是否变得生疏了？
Are you getting rusty?
天哪，他什么都知道。
Gosh, he knows everything.
他甚至想到了这一点。
He even had that in mind.
我们进去吧，查医生。
Let's go in, Dr. Cha.
哦，好的。
Oh, okay.
车恩才、
Cha Eunjae,
你是说你会去做那个手术吗？
are you saying
you will go into that surgery?
什么？
What?
你会参加这种冲动和鲁莽的手术吗？
You will participate
in that impulsive and reckless surgery?
这不是鲁莽。
It's not reckless.
他看到了我们看不到的东西。
He sees what we can't see.
金师傅在处理创伤方面有很多经验。
Master Kim has a lot of experience
dealing with trauma.
是的，这是正确的。
Yes, that's right.
不管它是谁、
Whoever it is,
无论他做什么或处于什么位置、
no matter what he does
or what position he is in,
他不去想别的事情。
he doesn't think about anything else.
他只是牢记一件事。
He just keeps one thing in mind.
拯救病人。
Save the patient.
无论怎样，都要救治病人。
Save the patient, no matter what.
这是金师傅教给我们的第一课。
That was Master Kim's first lesson
that he taught us.
你认为这是一个拯救人生命的手术吗？
Do you think that's a surgery
to save a person's life?
对于那个病人、
For that patient,
他作为运动员的生活是他生命的一部分。
his life as an athlete
is a part of his life.
你们这些人...
You guys…
是和他一样的疯狂。
are just as crazy as he is.
有时，有些水平是你不发疯就达不到的。
Sometimes, there are levels
that you can't reach without going crazy.
而金师傅...
And Master Kim…
称其为浪漫主义。
calls it romance.
浪漫？
Romance?
在一个人命关天的领域、
In a field
where people's lives are at stake,
他谈到了寻找浪漫的问题？
he talks about finding romance?
是的。
Yes.
这就是我们到现在为止一直在救人的方法，教授。
That's how we've been saving people
up until now, Professor.
车恩载，你不去吗？
Cha Eunjae, aren't you going?
如果没有，我就去。
If not, I'll go.
爸爸，我们以后再谈吧。
Dad, let's talk later.
吴镇。
Woojin.
浪漫？
Romance?
你说浪漫？
Romance, you say?
嗯。
Mm.
手术刀。
Scalpel.
(《浪漫医生》第三季)
(DR. ROMANTIC SEASON 3)
在所有的事情上...
In all things…
- 这是吐血。- 病人还没有死。
- It's hematemesis.
- The patient isn't dead yet.
...有基本原理和原则。
…there are fundamentals and principles.
他刚刚死于心脏衰竭。
He just died from heart failure.
无论这位老太太是否犯下纵火罪...
Whether this old lady
committed arson or not…
争论谁是好的，谁是坏的。
Debating over
who is good and who is bad.
嘿，你还不如去当法官或检察官呢
Hey. You may as well
go be a judge or prosecutor
而不是在这里!
instead of being here!
这是车金满教授今天上午发来的名单。
This is the list that
Professor Cha Jinman sent this morning.
他表现得好像他不会带任何人走。
He acted like he wouldn't
take anyone with him.
多尔达姆医院的急诊室怎么样了？
What about the emergency room
at Doldam Hospital?
这一刻，希望被证明是徒劳的、
The moment hope proves futile,
唯一剩下的就是残酷的现实。
the only thing left is the harsh reality.